

AMIE JOHNSTONE

Camberley, Surrey amiejohnstone18@gmail.com | 07764 967208 www.linkedin.com/in/amie-johnstone-07aa44b1 https://amiejohnstone18.github.io/CV/index.html

PERSONAL INTRODUCTION

I am an ambitious and hardworking individual with a passion for all things digital. Having recently completed a course in Full Stack Web Development and exploring all aspects involved, and with my professional background experience in digital Marketing and Communications, I have a keen eye for detail and excellent communication skills when either working within a team or liaising with clients. I have an independent ability to handle tasks with a methodical approach and ensure projects are completed to the highest standard and in the required time frame. For any knowledge I may initially lack, I make up for it by ensuring to learn fast and with complete understanding.

EDUCATION



Code Institute Diploma in Full Stack Web Development 2:1 – Second Class Honours

2020 - 2021

After graduating from University, I started Digital Marketing roles working closely with external Web Developers and took great interest in the different coding languages, along with the initial process from UX/UI design to website production. Realising this was a keen interest of mine, I enrolled in a Full Stack Web Development Diploma course at Code Institute (https://codeinstitute.net). They are the UK's only credit-rated coding Bootcamp, credited by the University of the West of Scotland (USW). The course took a year to complete and enabled me to develop skills in main coding languages HMTL, CSS, JavaScript, Python, and Django.

Along with main coding languages, the course also expanded on frameworks such as Bootstrap and Materialize, Application Program Interfaces (API's), jQuery, database programs such as MongoDB Atlas and relational database MySQL, deployment through GitHub pages (switching to PostgreSQL where applicable) and Heroku, Stripe payment system and Amazon Web Services.

I completed four milestone projects with Code Institute which were all built through GitHub using Gitpod. I used version control through Git to modify the repositories to produce a step-by-step log during development. Before starting the milestone development, I started with UX design by mapping out the 5 planes method of user experience and essentially created a business plan of customer and company objectives and requirements. I created wireframes for each project through using either Adobe Creative Suit programs or Balsamiq which assisted in the website development structure.

Modules studied in this course:

- HTML Fundamentals
- CSS Fundamentals
- User-Centric Frontend Development
- JavaScript Fundamentals
- Interactive Frontend Development

- Python Fundamentals
- Practical Python
- Data-centric Development
- Full stack frameworks with Django

GitHub profile: https://github.com/Amiejohnstone18



Canterbury Christ Church University Bachelor of Arts in Media and Communications 2:1 – Second Class Honours

First Year Modules:

- Research Skills
- Contemporary Media Debates
- Making Media, Meaning & Messages
- Media Consumption
- Introduction to Professional Communications
- Digital Media Practice

Second Year Modules:

- Popular Genres
- Media & Creative Industries
- Celebrity, News & The Media
- Writing for Media Communications
- Media & Society
- Creative Media & Communications Practice

Third Year Modules:

- Individual Research Project (Dissertation)
- Advertising Practices
- Youth Cultures
- Media Features
- Multi-Media Practice

Experienced in:

- InDesign
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- Premiere Pro / After Effects



Collingwood College Sixth Form

3 A*- C A-Levels (Media, Communications & Culture, Drama)

2012 - 2014



Collingwood College

5+ A* - C GCSE's (Including Maths and English)

2007 - 2012

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY



☐ The Glass Office People, Berkshire☐ Marketing Communications Manager

April 2019 - Present

Main responsibilities include:

- Defining and managing the brand- ensuring any external material is subject to company brand guidelines.
- Management of all social media platforms Instagram, Twitter, Facebook, and LinkedIn, including paid social media marketing campaigns.
- Manage Trustpilot Business and monitor reviews.
- Produce Email Marketing –whilst also keeping track of GDPR and updating a client database accordingly.
- Management of all external marketing and advertising communications, e.g. Online magazine editorials, radio advertisement, banner advertising, traditional print marketing.
- Worked alongside external Web Developers to implement any changes required on the website, along with using the Customer Management System (CMS) to update and produce new pages when necessary.
- Managed the relationship and budget with the external Google advertising agency, particularly focusing on Pay Per Click (PPC) and remarketing.
- Design of any marketing or advertising material/ campaigns.
- Working with a marketing budget and evolving on strategies to produce traffic results.
- Produce monthly reports with Google analytics, comparing all paid advertising channels.
- Keep up to date with alike companies to ensure we are offering a competitive product.
- Pay attention to the latest trends and styles to incorporate where possible.
- Design and produce all marketing and promotional materials.



Panarc interior solutions are the sister company of The Glass Office People. I had initially joined on a temp basis as an Accounts Assistant after coming back from Australia. With both companies wanting to advance on their marketing and advertising, I stayed to develop on these, therefore, roles and responsibilities for both are the same.

Accounts Assistant Main responsibilities include: March 2019 - Present

- Process incoming invoices and credit notes from suppliers into the integrity system Evolution M (Mardak).
- Checking supplier statements are up to date with invoices and payments.
- Manage employee credit card statements.
- Process fortnightly Subcontractor invoices to be raised for payment and send out payment certificate receipts to the Subcontractors.
- Manage company vehicles.
- Book out and keep track of employee holidays.
- Arrange for employee training as and when necessary.
- Create new job contracts on Mardak with the relevant information.
- Archive expired job contracts/ account admin.
- Handle purchasing of office equipment.
- Create purchase orders for ordering site materials.

Sanctuary Recruitment, Sydney, Australia Communications Manager (6- Month Contract) June 2018 – March 2019

IT Talent, Reading it talent Communications Manager (6- Month Contract) October 2017 – April 2018

Kurt Geiger, Canterbury Sales Assistant – Part-time (Student Study) January 2015 - July 2017

Next, Camberley Sales Assistant – Part-time (Student Study) July 2013 – July 2014

PROJECT S

All projects were completed during the Code Institute course as Module Exams. Wireframes for each can be found in the README.md files in my GitHub repositories https://github.com/Amiejohnstone18_

Milestone 1 - HIIT Fitness

https://amiejohnstone18.github.io/HIIT_Fitness/index.html

Built using main technologies HTML5 and CSS. The requirements for this project were to build a static website advertising a service or product for a company. I chose to build a gym website offering information on the class timetable, meet the PT team, where to sign up and how to contact the gym.

Milestone 2 - Happy Hour

https://amiejohnstone18.github.io/Happy-Hour/index.html

Happy Hour was built using main technologies HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript. The purpose of this project was to build a website, incorporating an API. After much research, I found a cocktail API and decide to create a website whereby a user can select a cocktail and be provided with its name, ingredients, rating, and image.

Please note: This API is no longer available for use.

Milestone 3 - The Baking Book

https://the-baking-book.herokuapp.com/index

The Baking Book was built using main technologies HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, and Python. The requirements for this project were to use CRUD functionality (Create, Read, Update, Delete) to give the user the ability to create a new receipt card, read it, update it, and also delete it. It is accessible for anyone to use CRUD on the website therefore recipe cards do regularly get deleted.

Milestone 4 - Willow Flowers

https://willow-flowers.herokuapp.com/

Willow Flowers was the 4th and final milestone project. This was built using main technologies HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Python, and Django. The purpose of this project was to ensure users were able to sign up and log in to personal accounts and access their saved data and purchase products. Also, the website owner was able to use CRUD to update the website with products when necessary.

PERSONAL INTERESTS

- Art & Design
- Travel
- Food
- Nature
- Animals
- Fitness